Samyukta M.M

Aspiring Human Resource Trainee

+917353808266 | samyuktamm175@gmail.com | Bengaluru, India.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Talent Acquisition Specialist with 1 year of experience looking to secure a challenging and rewarding position where I can utilize my skills and knowledge to help a company identify, attract, and hire top talent. In my current role, I have a proven track record of successfully identifying and attracting top talent, resulting in a high offer acceptance rate. I also have strong communication and interpersonal skills, with the ability to build relationships with candidates and hiring managers.

Notable Skills: Microsoft Office, Word, Excel, Time Management, Fast Learner, Tally.

EXPERIENCE

Carrernet | Talent Acquisition Specialist

May 2022 - Present

As a Talent Acquisition Specualist I have

- Led the full-cycle recruiting process for a variety of roles, including technical, sales, and marketing positions.
- Developed and implemented effective sourcing strategies, utilizing a range of tools and techniques, including job boards, social media, and employee referrals.
- Collaborated with hiring managers to understand their staffing needs and develop job descriptions that accurately reflected the role and its requirements.
- Reviewed resumes and conducted initial phone screenings with candidates to assess their qualifications and fit for the role.
- Conducted in-person interviews and facilitated the offer process, including negotiation and closing.
- Maintained accurate records and reporting on recruitment activities and metrics.
- Last but most importantly I also try giving unselected candidates proper feedback so that they can improve and develop their skills because I believe empathy is the most important trait any HR professional must possess.

ELITE IIT | Student Counselor | Bengaluru, India

Nov 2021 – May 2022

As Student Counselor I have

- Served as a Student Advisor, helping students to more clearly define and follow their academic path.
- Monitored student progress and performance, and maintained meticulous documentation for each student.

EDUCATION

MBA | Anjuman Institute of Technology and Management | Bhatkal

Oct 2019 - Sep 2021

• 74%

B.Com | Dr. A V Baliga college of commerce | Kumta

Jun 2016 - Jun 2019

• 79.24%

PUC | Dr. A V Baliga college of commerce | Kumta

• 84.33%

CASE STUDIES

NESTLE INDIA LTD

The scope of this project was to study the company & its continuous efforts to understand the changing lifestyle of India better and anticipate customer needs in order to provide Taste, Nutrition, Health and Wellness through its product offerings

EMPLOYEE RETENTION AND WORKFORCE SKILL MANAGEMENT

The scope of this study was to understand how companies can manage their employees with aspects to create better work-life balance, increase employee productivity without compromising on company culture & thereby increasing employee satisfaction & retention.